Nagendra Singh (Rahul)

 Polhi , India
 ■ rahulfaujdar662@gmail.com
 □ +919639800680
 □ in/rahulfaujdar

SUMMARY

I'm driven and able to adapt to challenges. After starting my BCA, I began working as a developer. My work

experience has included Javascript, Node Js, Express Js, AWS, Java, React Js, and other web and programming languages.

Experience working as part of an agile team, including prioritizing and scoping feature requests to guarantee that the most significant features were completed first.

I have experience developing full-stack web applications for analyzing and processing data as well as interacting with APIs, databases, and project managers.

Ability to building new Angular components for a web app which improved the time on the page for the average.

I've worked closely with the product manager, developers, and quality assurance team to determine testing methods, problems, and best practices for developing apps across various platforms.

I've designed and developed multi-platform apps using the latest industry adopted technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Intern

Technosters Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

March 2021 - August 2021, Agra, India

September 2021 - November 2022, Agra, India

• To develop software's using top javascript frameworks.

Full Stack Developer (Intern)

Technosters Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

- · To develop software's using top javascript frameworks.
- · Library React Js
- Backend Framework Express JS/Node JS
- · Database MySql, MSSQL, MongoDB
- · ORM Sequelize, Mongoose
- · Java, java servlet, jdbc

Software Engineer IOanyT Innovations

December 2022 - September 2023, Noida, India

- · To develop software's using AWS Web Services.
- · Implemented IAM best practices and role-based access control
- · Built serverless architecture with Lambda integrated with SNS, CloudWatch logs and other AWS services
- · Programming Languages: Node JS, JSON, YML
- · Built S3 buckets and managed policies for S3 buckets and used S3 bucket for storage and backup on AWS
- · Configured user accounts for Development, Test, Pre-Production and Production environments

Software Engineer

ТНР

September 2023 - Present, US

- · AWS-Centric Environment: Worked in a product-based company with a strong focus on leveraging AWS services.
- · Hands-on Experience: Actively utilized various AWS services in daily operations and project implementations.
- · Cloud Infrastructure Design: Collaborated with teams to architect scalable and resilient solutions using AWS services.
- · Resource Management: Managed cloud resources efficiently, optimizing performance and cost-effectiveness.
- · Security Implementation: Ensured the security of systems and data through robust AWS security measures.
- · Exploration of Emerging Technologies: Stayed updated with the latest AWS technologies to enhance product development processes.
- Innovation and Value Delivery: Contributed to driving innovation and delivering value to customers through scalable and reliable AWS-powered solutions.

PROJECTS

Bigainn

- · Bigainn is a trading stock organisation.
- · Created a Bigainn application in Node JS, Express JS, React Native, and MySQL.
- In this project, those who have no knowledge about the stock market will give their money to Bigainn, and Bigainn will invest their money in stocks on the customer's behalf with the help of experts.
- · Customers can view all their invested amounts, profits, and losses. If customers want to withdraw money, they will make a request for it.
- · After approval of the request, Begin will provide the requested amount to the respective customer. Customers can also deposit amounts for investing on different days.
- We also have a SIP calculator, which is based on SIP investments based on an estimated rate of return and the future value of your investment after a certain number of years.
- · We also have a notification facility that lets users know about all the profits and losses.
- · Bigainn admins can create managers and assign them roles that allow them to approve deposit and withdrawal requests.
- · In the dashboard, admins can create users, roles, and permissions. And can assign a particular role with permissions to a particular user.

Warehouse Management System

- · Created a warehouse management system in Node JS, Express JS, React JS, MSSQL, and AWS
- In this project, we have an admin panel from which admins can perform crud operations for roles and permissions. Create new users and assign them roles with permissions.
- · Admin can manage inventory item details, vendors, suppliers, customers, and purchase orders, and can also generate reports of all of them in an Excel file with the required filters.
- · We also have a customer panel from which customers can purchase inventory items with the quantity, price, cost, and all the other details.
- · We also manage customers payments; if any customer has some outstanding payments, some calculations are done at the backend to manage all the dues.
- · MSA report integration was also implemented, in which we generated a MSA report and sent it to the MSA server by connecting their server.

Lead Management System

- · Created a lead management system in Node JS, Express JS, React JS, and MYSQL
- In this project, telecallers call students and tell them about the institute, note all the talking, and take the date from the student and save it in the system to call him again.
- When the date arrives, the dashboard indicates the date to let the telecaller know that he or she needs to call that particular student on today's
- If a student wants to talk with a manager or team leader, then the telecaller can assign that lead to the particular role employee with whom the student wants to talk.
- · In the dashboard, admins can create users, roles, and permissions. And can assign a particular role with permissions to a particular user.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Applications (2020 - 2023)

Swami Vivekanand Subharti University • Meerut, Uttar Pradesh

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Software Developer Assessment

Coursera · 2022

· https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/HZUFN76VN28Y

Getting Started with Data Analytics on AWS

Coursera · 20222

· https://coursera.org/verify/F2PLDEDLDT4U

Introduction to Cloud Computing

Coursera · 2022

· https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/C23KUKWEN9L6

SKILLS

Database: MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

IDE & Tools: JetBrain Intellij, eclipse, VS Code, Postman, Github, Asana, Jira, Bitbucket

Stripe, Firebase, REST APIs, Agile and Scrum methodologies, Communication, Git, Linux, Web Sockets, Web Development

AWS Servies: CloudFormation, Lambda, API Gateway, S3, DynamoDB, Cognito, AWS SAM, SNS, SQS, SES, WAF, EC2, Route 53, Global Accelerator, CloudWatch, Rekognition, Comprehend, IAM, EventBridge, Systems Manager